Edoardo Gargano

Full-stack senior developer and JavaScript Advocate

via A. Bergamini 6, 40133, Bologna, IT

edoardo.gargano@gmail.com \$\mathbb{Q}\$ +39 329 54 166 26

🗘 Edoardo Gargano 💆 BolognaJS in Edoardo Gargano

Senior full-stack developer, Front-End Tech Lead, JavaScript Advocate and JS Bologna Community Organizer with more than 10 years of experience in multinational companies.

After successfully completing my Master's Degree in Computer Science at the University of Bologna, I worked for 3 years as full-stack developer at CINECA. Since 2011, I'm working in the technology department of YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP, leading a front-end development team.

During my free time, I organize the Bologna JavaScript Community in order to keep myself and other JavaScript lovers updated on the newest JavaScript ecosystem through talks, workshops and networking.

My strengths and passions: Node.is, React, Vue.is, JavaScript ecosystem.

SKILLS

Web Development	Leadership	Web Performance	Frameworks
Master	Master	Master	Advanced
html/html5 scss/css javascript analysis	team management and support teamwork problem solving time management	pwa response time lazy loading code splitting	reactjs vuejs redux/vuex jest
Testing	Software Engineering Advanced	Database	Agile
Advanced		Advanced	Advanced

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full-stack senior developer at MONRIF.NET (Bologna) 07/2020 - Today

http://www.monrifgroup.net/

I'm a full-stack developer with a deep knowledge of frontend and JavaScript.

I work on projects using Js ecosystem introducing JavaScript in the company.

Monrif.net, my actual company, wants an experienced JavaScript developer for the client and for the server side.

We are a highly skilled 5 people team, covering all positions from devops to backend/frontend.

I also try to do mentoring by facilitating colleagues to switch from python to JavaScript, and to improve the agile practices used.

As a Senior developer, here's what I do:

- Learn something new, everyday
- Work on large-scale, custom-designed, enterprise-level software development projects using JavaScript language and technologies.
- Champion agile best practices and Continuous Delivery
- Help the team to champion software excellence, craft technical vision and ensure we deliver value to our clients and their customers.
- Experience working with agile, Lean and/or Continuous Delivery approaches and best practices, such as Continuous Integration, TDD, BDD, etc.
- Knowledge of software best practices like Refactoring, Clean Code, Domain Driven Design, Encapsulation.
- Openness and adaptability you'll be working in a variety of settings and in a team-oriented, collaborative environment
- A coaching mentality as well as strong relationship-building skills at all levels
- All these things made with passion.
- Familiarity with few databases, like MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL, SQL Server, NoSQL.
- https://www.ilrestodelcarlino.it/
- https://www.ilgiorno.it/
- https://www.lanazione.it/
- https://www.quotidiano.net/

Key responsibilities

- Leading projects #LEAD
- Developing with quality #PROGRAMMING
- Developing testing strategies #TESTING
- Defining best practices to keep high software performances #PERFORMANCE
- Designing the evolutions of software products #EVOLUTION
- Refactor old tools and services #REFACTOR

- Leading planning activities and supporting in predictability #AGILE
- Defining and steering technical strategy with technical leads and architects#STRATEGY
- Supporting Project Managers #SUPPORT
- Team coaching and mentoring through workshops #MENTORING

Technologies

- HTML5, CSS3, JS
- React, Vanilla Js, Webpack, Node.js, Python
- NoSQL DB, Relational DB (Oracle, MySQL, Microsoft SQL)
- Strapi, Ghost, Stripe, Sanity, Gatsby, Next.js
- Git, Agile, Bash, AWS, Google Cloud

Front-End Tech Lead at YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP (Bologna) 2013 - 06/2020

http://www.ynap.com

My daily job is relative to team management, programming, planning, analysis of new functionalities and website performance enhancement, ensuring technical cohesion across the domain teams and acting as the technical domain representative in cross-domain matters.

My team is in charge of the following three luxury e-commerce websites, with focus on the development of new features, integration and refactorization of existing features, measuring and optimizing the website performances:

- https://www.balenciaga.com/
- https://www.alexandermcqueen.com/
- https://www.mcq.com/

Key responsibilities

- Leading a front-end development team #LEAD
- Developing in a number of programming languages, with quality #PROGRAMMING
- Developing testing strategies #TESTING
- Defining best practices to keep high software performances #PERFORMANCE
- Designing the evolutions of software products #EVOLUTION
- Leading planning activities and supporting in predictability #AGILE
- Defining and steering technical strategy with technical leads and architects#STRATEGY
- Supporting Project Managers and Product Managers #SUPPORT
- Team coaching and mentoring through workshops and communities #MENTORING

Technologies

- HTML5, CSS3, JS
- React, Vue.js and relative ecosystem
- NoSQL DB, Relational DB (Oracle, MySQL, Microsoft SQL)
- C#, RAZOR, MVC framework
- Website performance optimization
- Agile

Front-End Developer (Consultant) at YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP (Bologna) 2011 - 2013

http://www.ynap.com

As consultant, I was in charge of the development and maintenance of e-commerce websites powered by YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP.

Main activities

- Restyling of existing websites and adding new features and functionalities
- Front-End optimization (pixel perfection from layouts,...) and mapping and skinning functionalities from backend side
- Bug fixing
- Web performance optimization
- Technologies used: ASP, HTML5, CSS (CSS3), JavaScript, XSL, MVC Razor, Agile

PHP Developer and Web developer at CINECA (Bologna) 2009 - 2011

https://cineca.it

I started my professional career developing web applications working with PHP and Oracle Databases.

Main activities

- Development of web applications for clinical trials and pharmaceutical procedures
- Creation and maintenance of the internal Help Desk application
- Development of corporate websites in Drupal and Wordpress

VOLUNTEER

Organiser at Bologna JavaScript Community/Meetup

http://bolognajs.com/

BolognaJS is a community for JavaScript developers in Bologna. We made workshops, talks, networking meetings, we believe in sharing knowledge and we study new technologies on JavaScript ecosystem. I love to meet people and to speak about Programming feature, technique and do something together.

See our last meetup on: https://www.meetup.com/Bologna-JS-Meetup/

EDUCATION

Master's degree in Computer Science at University of Bologna (UniBo) **2005 - 2008**

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science at University of Bologna (UniBo) **2001 - 2005**

LANGUAGES

Italian

Native speaker

English

Fluent

INTERESTS

LEGO

I build some original creations: https://www.flickr.com/photos/eldedo/

REFERENCES

Nicola Cuccurazzu

Senior Product Owner, YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP

Very competent in web sphere and it's pleasant to work with him 'cause he is able to mix seriousness and professionalism with a great deal of sympathy.

Giuseppe Mandato

Software Engineer, Elsevier

I've had the privilege of working with Edoardo for a couple of months, I joined its team in a very stressful period, the project deadline was strict and the company had large expectations. Despite everything Edoardo made the journey like a peaceful walk, thanks to its technical and relational skills we met the deadline and it was even funny. I was impressed by the trust he has given me. Absolutely one of the best Tech Lead I ever had.